Guide to the Office of the Chancellor and Executive Vice President 1952-1966 RG 6.0
New York University Libraries, Publisher
- Series I: David D. Henry/Carroll V. Newsom
  - Subseries A: Administrative
    - Smith, Rufus - Provost, 1951-1954; bar code: 3 1142 042254824 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - University College, 1952-1954; bar code: 3 1142 042254824 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - University College, 1954-1955; bar code: 3 1142 042254824 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - University Physician, Office of, 1955; bar code: 3 1142 042254824 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Voorhis, Harold O. - Vice Chancellor and Secretary, 1952-1953; bar code: 3 1142 042254824 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Voorhis, Harold O. - Vice Chancellor and Secretary, 1953; bar code: 3 1142 042254824 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Washington Square College, 1952-1953; bar code: 3 1142 042254824 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Washington Square College, 1953-1954; bar code: 3 1142 042254824 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Washington Square College, 1954; bar code: 3 1142 042254824 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Washington Square College, 1954-1955; bar code: 3 1142 042254824 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Separation Folder, bar code: 3 1142 042254824 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Subseries B: Educational Television
    Records pertaining to educational television have been described in a separate finding aid.
    - Addresses - META Personnel and Interested Individuals, undated; bar code: 3 1142 042255474 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ad Hoc TV Group, 1954-1955; bar code: 3 1142 042255474 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Council on Education, Committee on Education, 1952-1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255474 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Council on Education, Committee on Education, 1954-1955; bar code: 3 1142 042255474 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, 1953-1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255474 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, 1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255474 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, 1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255474 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, 1954-1955; bar code: 3 1142 042255474 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, 1955-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255474 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, 1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255474 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Board of Trustees, Distribution, 1954-1955; bar code: 3 1142 042255474 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Board of Trustees, Identification, 1954-1955; bar code: 3 1142 042255474 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Board of Trustees, Membership, 1953-1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255482 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Board of Trustees, Membership, 1954-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255482 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Board of Trustees, Minutes, 1953-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255482 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - By-Laws, Proposed and Adopted, 1953-1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255482 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Charter, Application for, 1953; bar code: 3 1142 042255482 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Executive Committee, Correspondence, 1955; bar code: 3 1142 042255482 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Executive Committee, Correspondence, 1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255482 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Executive Committee, Minutes, 1955-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255482 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Executive Director, Correspondence, 1955; bar code: 3 1142 042255482 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Executive Director, Correspondence, 1955; bar code: 3 1142 042255482 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Executive Director, Correspondence, 1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255482 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Executive Director, Correspondence, 1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255482 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Executive Director, Correspondence, 1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255482 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Facilities and Equipment, 1953; bar code: 3 1142 042255490 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Facilities and Equipment, 1953-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255490 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Finance Committee, 1955-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255490 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Friends of TV, 1953-1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255490 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Fundraising, 1953-1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255490 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Fundraising, 1955-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255490 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Incorporation, 1953; bar code: 3 1142 042255490 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Incorporation, 1953-1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255490 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Incorporation, 1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255490 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Metropolitan New York Educational Agencies Committee, Correspondence, 1952-1953; bar code: 3 1142 042255508 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Metropolitan New York Educational Agencies Committee, Correspondence, 1953-1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255508 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - META, General Correspondence, 1953; bar code: 3 1142 042255508 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - META, General Correspondence, 1953-1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255508 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - META, General Correspondence, 1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255508 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - META, General Correspondence, 1955-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255508 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1953-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255508 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - New York State, Correspondence, 1952-1953; bar code: 3 1142 042255508 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - New York State, Correspondence, 1953; bar code: 3 1142 042255508 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Nominating Committee, 1954-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255508 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Operating Statements, 1955-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255516 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Organizing Committee, 1953-1954; bar code: 3 1142 042255516 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Pamphlets and Publications, 1952-1953; bar code: 3 1142 042255516 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Pamphlets and Publications, 1953; bar code: 3 1142 042255516 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Pamphlets and Publications, 1954-1955; bar code: 3 1142 042255516 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Pamphlets and Publications, 1954-1955; bar code: 3 1142 042255516 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Personnel, Committee on, 1955; bar code: 3 1142 042255516 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Production Center, 1954-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255516 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Program Advisory Committee, 1954-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255516 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Program Development Director, Candidates for, 1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255516 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Treasurer, 1955; bar code: 3 1142 042255516 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - UHF/VHF Transmission, 1954-1955; bar code: 3 1142 042255516 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - UHF/VHF Transmission, 1955-1956; bar code: 3 1142 042255516 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Subseries C: Speeches and Biographical Material
    The third series in this subgroup represents the public side of David Henry during the years 1952-1955, with one file containing material as far back as 1949. Henry made frequent speaking engagements and public appearances to promote his interests in educational strategies and techniques such as the use of film, television and computers, along with foreign exchange and urban outreach programs. NYU dedications, and speeches to NYU associations and councils are also included. The series measures .5 linear feet.
    - Biographical Material, 1952-1955; bar code: 3 1142 042254832 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Speeches, 1955; bar code: 3 1142 042254832 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Speeches, 1955; bar code: 3 1142 042254832 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Speeches, 1954-1955; bar code: 3 1142 042254832 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Speeches, 1954; bar code: 3 1142 042254832 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Speeches, 1954; bar code: 3 1142 042254832 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Speeches, 1954; bar code: 3 1142 042254832 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Speeches, 1954; bar code: 3 1142 042254840 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Speeches, 19531954; bar code: 3 1142 042254840 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Speeches, 1952-1953; bar code: 3 1142 042254840 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Speeches (before arrival at NYU), 1949-1952; bar code: 3 1142 042254840 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Series II: John E. Ivey, Jr.
  The records of John E. Ivey Jr. measure approximately 6.3 linear feet. The bulk of the material spans the years 1957-1959, with some files dating back to 1954. This subgroup has been processed into one administrative series containing 17 subseries. Certain files covering student problems, faculty appointments and the selection of Deans are restricted.
  The records exhibit many of the changes occurring at NYU during this period, such as the introduction of all university departments, a point of contention between the administration and the Deans (see subseries III & XV), and an increased awareness of international affairs during the height of the Cold War. A subseries on international affairs (XII) contains material on the Center for International Affairs, the Brazilian Institute, Israel and a ground breaking Soviet-U.S. engineering exchange program.
  The volume of records pertaining to international affairs is just one example of Ivey's more extraverted approach to NYU's educational mission than that of his predecessors. The files reflect a continuing involvement in educational television (subseries XVIII), while demonstrating the emergence of other technological advances in the field of education, such as the language laboratory (Box 4/Fldr. 1) and improved computer facilities (Box 3/Fldr. 13). In addition, a subseries on special projects (XVI) conveys the sense of a new creative spirit at NYU during the late 1950's and leading into the early 1960's. There are files on various arts groups, an experimental liberal arts program, atomic energy, and many research ventures, programs and proposals. Finally, a file on the American Association of University Professors contains further information on the case of Edwin Berry Burgum, the Professor dismissed for being a member of the Communist Party (Box 3/Fldr. 6).
  - Subseries A: Administration
    - Business Office, 1957-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254857 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Business Office, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254857 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - By-Laws and Charter Faculty Handbook, 1955-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254857 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Educational Services, Office of, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254857 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Executive Vice-President - Manual of Functions and Responsibilities, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254857 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Institutional Research, Office of - John Dale Russell, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254857 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - institutional Research, Office of, 1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254857 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Long Range Study and Planning, 1956-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254857 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Long Range Study and Planning, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254857 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - President, Office of - Carrol V. Newsom, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254857 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Summer Session, Director of, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254865 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Vice-President and Secretary, Office of - Harold O. Voorhis, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254865 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B: Admissions
    - Admissions Office, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254865 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Dean of Registration and Financial Aid, Office of, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254865 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Enrollment and Registration, 1956-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254865 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Registrar, Office of, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254865 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Subseries C: All-University Departments
    - Annual Reports A-B, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254865 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Annual Reports D-M, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254865 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Annual Reports P-W, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254865 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Meetings of Department Heads, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254873 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Policies and Procedures, 1956-1957; bar code: 3 1142 042254873 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Policies and Procedures, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254873 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Professional School Cooperation, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254873 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Relationship of Commerce and Education, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254873 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Subseries D: Associations, Educational
    - American Association of University Professors, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254873 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - American Council on Education, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254873 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - National Commission on Accrediting, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254873 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Regional Systems (NEBE & WICHE), 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254873 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - New York State Educational Department, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254873 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Subseries E: Committees
    - Academic Advisory Council, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254873 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - College Qualification Center, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254873 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Computing Facilities, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254873 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Coordinated Language Study, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Committee on Academic Personnel - Salary Administration, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Geophysical Institute, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Glen Ridge High School, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Provisional Admissions, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Registration Policies and Procedures, 1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Statistics, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Task Force Operations, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Task Force Operations, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Task Force Operations, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Television, All-University Committee on, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Tuition Evaluation, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Subseries F: Correspondence
    - Correspondence A-B, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence C-D, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence E-I, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254881 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence J-P, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254899 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence Q, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254899 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence R, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254899 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence S-T, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254899 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence U-Z, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254899 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Subseries G: Deans
    - Graduate School of Arts and Science (Selection of New Dean), 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254899 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Graduate School of Arts and Science (Selection of New Dean), 1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254899 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Graduate School of Public Administration and Social Service, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254899 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - University College (Selection of New Dean), 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254899 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Subseries H: Faculty
    - Commendations, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254907 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - University Senate, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254907 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Utilization, 1957-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254907 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Subseries I: Fundraising
    - Albert Gallatin Associates, 1956-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254907 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Alumni Federation, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254907 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Development, University, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254907 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Ford Foundation, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254907 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Grants and Gifts, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254907 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Duplicates - Chancellor's Correspondence; A-Ae, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254907 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Duplicates - Chancellor's Correspondence; B-G, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254907 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Photographs separated from University Development, undated; bar code: 3 1142 042254907 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Subseries J: Government, Federal
    - National Science Foundation, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254915 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Office of Education, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254915 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Subseries K: Heights Campus
    - Heights Campus, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254915 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Dormitory, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254915 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Technology Building #1, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254915 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Provost, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254915 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Subseries L: International Affairs
    - Brazilian Institute, 1953-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254915 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Center for International Affairs (Trager), 1957-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254915 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Center for International Affairs (Operation), 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254915 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Center for International Affairs, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254923 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Center for International Affairs, 1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254923 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Wallace Clark Center for International Management, 1956-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254923 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - International Conference of Scientific Information, 1957; bar code: 3 1142 042254923 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Institute for United Nations Study and Research (NYU and MSU), 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254923 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - International Seminar in Instructional TV and Radio, 1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254923 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Israel, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254923 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Israel, 1959-1960; bar code: 3 1142 042254923 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Powers, Phillip N., 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254931 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - SE Asia Regional Education Project and Nuclear Center, 1957-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254931 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Soviet-U.S. Engineering Exchange Program, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254931 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - United Nations - GPASS (Program for Training Administrators), 1957; bar code: 3 1142 042254931 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Subseries M: Miscellaneous
    - Free European University, 1957-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254931 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - University Health Services, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254931 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - University Press, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254931 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Subseries L: Personnel
    - Personnel Division, 1956-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254931 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Prospective Personnel, 1957; bar code: 3 1142 042254931 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Subseries N: Schools
    - Athletics, Division of, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254931 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Commerce, School of, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254931 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Commerce, School of, 1956-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254949 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Dentistry, School of, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254949 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Education, School of, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254949 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Education, School of, 1957-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254949 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Engineering, School of, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254949 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Engineering, School of, 1956-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254949 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Fine Arts, Institute of, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254949 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - General Division, Division of, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254949 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Graduate School of Arts and Science, 1956-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254956 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Graduate School of Public Administration and Social Service, 1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254956 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Graduate School of Public Administration and Social Service, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254956 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Graduate School of Public Administration and Social Service (Program), 1954-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254956 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Graduate School of Public Administration and Social Service (Program), 1954-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254956 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Graduate School of Business Administration, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254956 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Graduate School of Business Administration, 1957-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254956 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Law, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254956 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Medical Center, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254964 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Medical Center, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254964 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - OSSBI (Office of Special Services to Business and Industry), 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254964 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - School of Retailing, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254964 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - University College of Arts and Science, 1956-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254964 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Washington Square College of Arts and Science, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254964 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Subseries O: Special Projects
    - Academy of Aeronautics, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254964 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - American Academy of Dramatic Arts, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254964 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Office of Applied Social Research Associates, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254964 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Institute for Archaeological Research, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254964 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Atomic Energy, 1957; bar code: 3 1142 042254964 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Bell Telephone Labs Program in Engineering, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254964 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Communication Arts Group, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Continution Education Center, 1957-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Experimental Liberal Arts Program, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - French House, 19571958; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Hall of American Studies, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Herald Tribune Fresh Air Fund, 1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Higher Education, Center for Study and Development of, 1957-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Institute for Industrial Behavior, 19571958; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Learned Societies, 19581959; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 19561958; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - NEA-NYU Seminar - Creativity in American Culture, 1957; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Post-Doctoral Program in Psychology, 19551958; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Graduate Institute of Book Publishing, 19571959; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Rehabilitation Services Center, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Rehabilitation Services Center, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254972 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Rehabilitation Services Center, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254980 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Research, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254980 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Research, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254980 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Social Work Education (Pre-Professional Curriculum), 1956-1957; bar code: 3 1142 042254980 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Summer Theater Seminar and Workshop, University Heights, 1955-1958; bar code: 3 1142 042254980 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Town Hall, 1957-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254980 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Subseries O: Students
    - Dean of Students, 1958-1959; bar code: 3 1142 042254980 (Box 24, Folder 7)